<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
 
 <title>Zen Savona</title>
 <link href="http://zen.id.au/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://zen.id.au"/>
 <updated>2013-01-21T11:49:49+10:00</updated>
 <id>http://zen.id.au</id>
 <author>
   <name>Zen Savona</name>
   <email>z@zensavona.com</email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>Github for government</title>
   <link href="http://zen.id.au/2013/github-for-government"/>
   <updated>2013-01-21T00:00:00+10:00</updated>
   <id>http://zen.id.au/2013/github-for-government</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m a big fan of both &lt;a href='http://git-scm.com'&gt;Git&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href='http://github.com'&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt; (both as a product and as a company - it&amp;#8217;s made by a bunch of seriously cool people) and I think that a thing like Github is (with a few pretty minor tweaks) what we need to bring our 19th century governments into the 21st century.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id='our_popular_democratic_government_systems_are_fundamentally_broken_by_design'&gt;Our popular democratic government systems are fundamentally broken by design&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Let me prefix this: I am Australian and live in Australia, I understand that most of the people reading this will be in America and maybe Europe, so let&amp;#8217;s not argue over details but look at the ideas most of the world&amp;#8217;s democratic government systems are based upon - they are all pretty similar in concept. My understanding of the way even our government works is quite limited, but I will do my best to present my ideas - if I am erroneous please let me know&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seems to me that representative government is designed to solve the following problem: &lt;em&gt;people have different views and beliefs; in order to develop policies which best represent the group as a whole, we elect people whom we believe best echo our views and interests to represent us in the creation and uphold of laws.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ideally, everyone should be able to represent their own unique views on every issue individually. When you have 21 million people who each have slightly differing views on issues, this becomes difficult for a couple of reasons:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you tried to put all those people in a room and consider every single opinion, it would take so long that nothing would get done&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Not everyone has the time to go sit in a room arguing about laws all the time, and it seems unfair that a person shouldn&amp;#8217;t have their view/s represented because they don&amp;#8217;t have time to argue it &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; These are legitimate problems and it seems this is the reason our current models of government have stuck around so long. Although our present government models kind of work, there are some serious issues: &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;When you elect an &lt;em&gt;individual&lt;/em&gt; to represent your interests, they are always going to have their own interests as well. It&amp;#8217;s human nature to put your own interests first and until the human mind completely changes corruption and self serving lawmaking is always going to be an issue.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Because of the amount of interaction, voting parties and the general inefficiency of the whole system, the time frame from realising a change needs to be made (even if the majority agrees on this) and actually applying a real law is sometimes many years.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The process for an individual to propose a change to the law and actually have that suggestion heard is often long, unclear and off-putting unless they are already heavily involved in politics.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Running a system of parliament and employing all the people needed to make such a system work in hugely expensive and resource hungry.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The amount of formal and informal education required to even think about contributing to politics is extremely prohibitive to &amp;#8216;normal people&amp;#8217;. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id='github_for_government'&gt;Github for government&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seems that the technology we have right now (computers, smartphones, widespread availability of internet) could solve most of these problems and provide a much better system. Admittedly I haven&amp;#8217;t considered a lot of details - but I&amp;#8217;d like to present the basic idea and get some feedback.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I propose is a Github-esque system of collaborative document editing/versioning/merging for legal documents and laws. Imagine how unimaginably fucking fantastic it would be if I as a regular dude could go fork some law, change some things around, make a pull request and if approved by a group of maintainers (not sure how these people would be elected? Perhaps the whole thing would need a reputation based moderation system a la &lt;a href='http://stackoverflow.com'&gt;StackOverflow&lt;/a&gt;?) be voted on by the general public. I think that would be amazing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id='what_this_would_mean_for_government_as_we_know_it'&gt;What this would mean for government as we know it&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our whole system of party politics could be thrown out, and with it all the bias and relationship bullshit that comes with it. Everyone could vote on and discuss individual, modular issues which are completely separate to each other - it seems obvious that government should be done this way. Why do I need to agree with &lt;em&gt;everything&lt;/em&gt; some particular politician thinks? What if one person represents my views relating to education and health, but I completely disagree with their policy regarding same sex marriage and the environment? Why can&amp;#8217;t I have the best of all the opinions across all members of all parties? Why do we even have parties if such a collaborative, distributed, modular approach to government is possible?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id='everyone_can_participate'&gt;Everyone can participate&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we were to implement such a system, those with smartphones could download a Government app and receive notifications when there is a new proposed change to vote on. If they don&amp;#8217;t particularly care about certain issues, they could choose to &amp;#8216;follow&amp;#8217; certain &amp;#8216;repositories&amp;#8217; of laws. Those without smartphones could receive an email notifying them that there is a new change to vote on. There would probably need to be some amount of buffer time between proposing a law change and deciding that it&amp;#8217;s agreed upon (maybe something like 30-45 days could be allowed to give everyone time to review changes and check their email), but I don&amp;#8217;t think every single person should necessarily have to vote on every single issue - you shouldn&amp;#8217;t be forced to make a decision on something you don&amp;#8217;t care about or know enough about to feel you can make educated judgement. There should certainly be a minimum number (somewhat like the Whitehouse&amp;#8217;s threshold for proposals to be reviewed, maybe there would be some kind of minimum stars or votes for a pull-request to be reviewed and go to a public vote for approval? Just thinking aloud here)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There could be a global changelog on the homepage, showing all the changes in chronological order, people could subscribe to notifications and be alerted when this changes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id='lets_do_it'&gt;Let&amp;#8217;s do it&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I understand that ripping the current government system out by the roots sounds crazy and impossible, but throughout history bigger changes have happened. I think there would be an incredible amount of public support for something like this if there is a way of explaining this system to regular people and educating them as to how it could benefit them. It certainly needs a whole lot more thought and detail, and if you have any ideas, thoughts or feedback (positive or negative) I would love to hear them.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>My first tablet - a review of the iPad 1</title>
   <link href="http://zen.id.au/2012/my-first-tablet---a-review-of-the-ipad-1"/>
   <updated>2012-12-13T00:00:00+10:00</updated>
   <id>http://zen.id.au/2012/my-first-tablet---a-review-of-the-ipad-1</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I am a developer but I think although I have no real experience in graphic design or UX I have a good eye for product design and user experience. I&amp;#8217;ve mainly used android phones and tablets, so this review comes with that in mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I happened to have an iPad 1 64GB 3G offered to me for a stupidly small amount of money - although I didn&amp;#8217;t really plan on buying one, I couldn&amp;#8217;t pass it up and thought I&amp;#8217;ll find out what all the fuss is about. My main computers are a current generation MacBook Pro 15&amp;#8221; and a fairly beefy Linux desktop. I take my MacBook with me places, so if I can replace some of it&amp;#8217;s duties with something a third of the weight and size that would be nice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id='the_ipad_and_ios'&gt;The iPad and iOS&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First impressions so far are that it is a really good idea but needs refining, it&amp;#8217;s not quite right in some respects. I use it for both consuming and creating content, so input is very important for me - I like to write blog posts, emails and reasonably long comments and responses on various websites (no coding, I save that for a proper keyboard). I find it just slightly too slow for regular browsing and app usage coming from a Galaxy Nexus phone, it&amp;#8217;s definitely less buggy and jerky in it&amp;#8217;s OS and software next to android 4.1. The best way i can describe what using the OS feels like coming from someone who has used pretty much exclusively android for the last few years is like using a manual typewriter versus an electric one - it is slow but still responsive and elegant. My android phone (and all the tablets out there I&amp;#8217;ve used) feel much faster in terms of things loading, pages rendering etc but the actual experience on the iPad is much smoother (although slower) because the UI doesn&amp;#8217;t freeze or become buggy and erratic when doing something intensive. It will rarely freeze and skip pages or any other unexpected behavior that Android users have come to expect. I am often pleasantly surprised by it&amp;#8217;s accuracy and intuitiveness when it comes to things like copypasting, selecting text and other really simple functionality that android struggles to make easy and obvious. I think the current generation iPad will be a Windows to Mac kind of feeling from my android phone experience, especially with the smart cover - being able to angle it on tables and my lap&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The things I use the most are Safari, Twitter, Mail.app, Facebook and iA writer (what I&amp;#8217;m writing this blog post with right now). I would like to use Chrome and GMail but I find on he first gen iPad they are noticeably slow compared to apple&amp;#8217;s (more) native apps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id='ia_writer'&gt;iA Writer&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;iA Writer is a beautiful piece of software. Everything In it is so intuitive, well thought out and nicely implemented (even more impressively so than than the Mac app in my opinion). It looks and feels like it has been built by &lt;a href='http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Mythical_Man-Month#The_surgical_team'&gt;a surgeon&lt;/a&gt;. The iCloud and Dropbox integration is flawless and the extended keyboard is fantastic - The only things I would change are the addition of a &amp;#8216;delete&amp;#8217; key, although I never used this in the past, the more time I spend in front of my desktop the more I see myself reaching for this on my MacBook (and now iPad) and the option to use the extended keyboard all over the OS as a replacement (I&amp;#8217;m not sure how possible this is?)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id='conclusions'&gt;Conclusions&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can see that many of the things which bother me have been solved with the later generations of the device (smart cover to tilt it, faster processor, lighter etc) - my only issue which isn&amp;#8217;t solved is the actual screen size. I find that the touchscreen keyboard is surprisingly comfortable to use considering that it&amp;#8217;s a piece of glass, but it&amp;#8217;s about half an inch to an inch too small to fit my whole two hands over it (I have fairly large hands and fingers). If it were slightly larger and the processor were faster (a la current generation iPad) I can envisage myself touch typing effectively. Maybe I need to play with the Microsoft Surface and it&amp;#8217;s slightly larger screen? I will have to investigate and write a follow up in the future.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>How long till Apple makes a touchscreen iMac?</title>
   <link href="http://zen.id.au/2012/how-long-till-apple-makes-a-touchscreen-imac"/>
   <updated>2012-12-08T00:00:00+10:00</updated>
   <id>http://zen.id.au/2012/how-long-till-apple-makes-a-touchscreen-imac</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I had a strange dream last night (seriously, you know you have issues when your &lt;em&gt;dream is set in an Apple store&lt;/em&gt;). So I was in the Apple store trying to explain the iMac to my mum - I picked up an iPad and explained to her that the iMac is essentially just a big iPad. I proceeded to swipe and tap the iMac&amp;#8217;s 27&amp;#8221; screen just like I would the iPad. It worked beautifully - this makes me remember how before the iPad there were plethoras of &amp;#8216;tablet PCs&amp;#8217; which never really took off; Apple came along, did it right and a few short years later iPads are eating the consumer PC market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wonder if they can do the same with touchscreen PCs&amp;#8230; (HP Touchsmart, anyone?).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just food for thought, but with OS X becoming more and more &amp;#8216;iOS-y&amp;#8217; and the rise of Windows 8 touchscreen laptops (a la Lenovo Yoga 13) this would make a whole lot of sense, wouldn&amp;#8217;t it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me know what you think.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Don't be a hater</title>
   <link href="http://zen.id.au/2012/dont-be-a-hater"/>
   <updated>2012-12-03T00:00:00+10:00</updated>
   <id>http://zen.id.au/2012/dont-be-a-hater</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;100% of haters are unrealized potential &amp;#8230; (for example) Michael Jordan&amp;#8217;s not a hater, when you get to that level you don&amp;#8217;t have time to hate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a really important point that &lt;a href='http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=CJv5Nc4Hl8k'&gt;Joe Rogan and Byran Callen&lt;/a&gt; make, if you&amp;#8217;re doing something awesome and you&amp;#8217;re good at it you have no time or desire to point out and pick on the shortcomings of other people - if they&amp;#8217;re going to fail that&amp;#8217;s usually obvious and they can manage that by themselves, you don&amp;#8217;t need to help them along or point it out in a narcissistic way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As much as the tech community likes to think that we embrace trying and failure, we still have a horrible culture of putting shit on each other (often on Hacker News or our blogs) - unless someone does something particularly nasty to you personally there is really no need to do this - what is it going to achieve? It seems like every day there is at least one or two posts on HN which are some form of non-constructive criticism about someone else&amp;#8217;s opinion or project. If you really gave a shit and wanted to help them rather than just trying to grab a little bit of the spotlight, you&amp;#8217;d email them privately with something like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hey John, I noticed you&amp;#8217;re doing ____, I happened to do that before on a project of my own and if you use _____ instead it will probably save you a ton of headaches. Good luck!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s as simple as that, it&amp;#8217;ll take you all of 10 minutes rather than an hour to write a long rant of a blog post and you might actually help the guy rather than publicly put them down. Just think about why you&amp;#8217;re writing things for a moment before you put (metaphorical) pen to paper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That concludes my hater-hating rant.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>On trust</title>
   <link href="http://zen.id.au/2012/on-trust"/>
   <updated>2012-11-17T00:00:00+10:00</updated>
   <id>http://zen.id.au/2012/on-trust</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In retrospect, this seems obvious - but I think all real realisations are that way, aren&amp;#8217;t they?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve been told by many people throughout my life to &amp;#8220;only ever trust yourself&amp;#8221; - I never really interpreted this correctly and as a result, thought it was some closed minded and shitty advice; turns out I was wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id='only_trusting_yourself_vs_trusting_yourself_to_judge_others'&gt;Only trusting yourself vs. trusting yourself to judge others&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The really important differentiation here is between &amp;#8220;only trusting yourself&amp;#8221; (or more specifically, the implication of not trusting anyone else) and trusting your instincts (which I think is a much better way of putting this idea). Trusting your instincts is extremely important - sometimes they&amp;#8217;re wrong, but most of the time they aren&amp;#8217;t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id='if_you_feel_deep_down_that_you_can_entrust_your_life_to_a_person_trust_your_own_judgement'&gt;If you feel deep down that you can entrust your life to a person, trust your own judgement.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sounds ludicrous right? But really, if you don’t think you can rely on your own &lt;span&gt;seemingly rash&lt;/span&gt; judgement, how do you feel comfortable trusting anyone else’s judgement? It makes no sense. In the last 6 months or so I’ve rapidly become a much more confident person, much of this I attribute to trusting myself; there are more instances than I care to mention where I’ve acted upon someone else’s advice (in the past) in spite of my gut feeling being different, only to realise months (or years) later that I was right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id='trust_yourself_take_risks_and_own_your_failures'&gt;Trust yourself, take risks and own your failures&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sounds obvious and silly to the initiated, but I wish I had the sense to realise this a long time ago.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Get your shit together, people</title>
   <link href="http://zen.id.au/2012/get-your-shit-together-people"/>
   <updated>2012-09-03T00:00:00+10:00</updated>
   <id>http://zen.id.au/2012/get-your-shit-together-people</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Disclaimer: I live in Brisbane, Australia. My only real window to what is happening in silicon valley is HN and the blogs of various founders and VCs from the valley. If my assumptions are completely wrong, please do let me know.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id='shitty_products'&gt;Shitty products&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right now in the world there are so many talented and skilled developers - why are so many of us working on such shitty, menial ideas? I mean there are exceptions - but it also seems like there are &lt;i&gt;so many&lt;/i&gt; people working on &lt;i&gt;really stupid things&lt;/i&gt;. No, I &lt;i&gt;don't&lt;/i&gt; want to sign up to your bootstrap themed product which looks like it was thrown together in a week and performs no valuable purpose to my daily life (which I can&amp;#8217;t replicate more elegantly with a text file). It seems like we are becoming so intent on &amp;#8216;shipping&amp;#8217; &lt;i&gt;something&lt;/i&gt;, that we are willing to throw &lt;i&gt;anything&lt;/i&gt; out there and hope that by chance, we make something that &lt;i&gt;someone, somewhere&lt;/i&gt; wants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='http://mariusandra.com/blog/2012/08/stop-producing-shit/'&gt;This article&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href='http://mariusandra.com/'&gt;Marius Andra&lt;/a&gt; really struck a chord with me and somewhat inspired this post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A friend of mine is starting what can only be described as a combination of Facebook, Groupon, LinkedIn and Foursquare. He’s super excited and hasn’t talked to any potential customers yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know a guy whose startup pivots twice a year, each time hoping to solve a problem that’s not really there. Now they’re cloning Yammer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some other guys had an idea, received validation from two potential clients, raised funding, hired a lot of people, built a product and discovered nobody really wants to pay for it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#8217;s a thought, spend more time on something which you know is great, and launch it with polish. Don&amp;#8217;t ship your &lt;i&gt;shitty, half baked product&lt;/i&gt; - launch it well and give people something to gasp at. Until then, keep thinking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id='the_startup_romantic_era'&gt;The startup &amp;#8220;romantic era&amp;#8221;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are treating business like it&amp;#8217;s a fucking &lt;i&gt;art form&lt;/i&gt;. If you haven&amp;#8217;t already seen this, read a couple of posts on &lt;a href='http://doublestealth.blogspot.com'&gt;Double Stealth&lt;/a&gt;, if this sounds anything like you, go find a mirror, look into it for a long time and seriously thing about what you doing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember this: business is about selling things to people. People are just like you - if you are working on something which you would not personally &lt;strong&gt;stand outside in the cold for a couple of hours to pay money for&lt;/strong&gt;, you&amp;#8217;re probably doing it wrong (Well, not quite to that extent, but I&amp;#8217;m sure you know what I mean).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src='http://www-bgr-com.vimg.net/wp-content/uploads/2012/01/beijingchina-iphone-4s-launch.jpeg' alt='People waiting to buy some cool-ass shiny Apple shit' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other thing to remember is that most consumers &lt;i&gt;do not really care&lt;/i&gt; about (or understand) how your product is &lt;i&gt;slightly better&lt;/i&gt; in some way than what they use right now - for them, it&amp;#8217;s much easier to stick with writing shit down on a piece of paper than figure out how to use your swanky web-based AJAXy responsive &amp;#8216;disruptive&amp;#8217; to-do list which syncs between multiple devices and uses local storage for fast access to data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Give them something they are &lt;strong&gt;genuinely amazed by&lt;/strong&gt; - I remember when I first saw an iPhone 3G in the flesh (the original iPhone was never released in Australia). My friend came over to my place one afternoon and showed me this new phone of his (at the time I had one of &lt;a href='http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/HTC_TyTN_II'&gt;these babies&lt;/a&gt;, a HTC TyTN II) I had never used a capacitive touchscreen before and thought it was &lt;strong&gt;fucking magical&lt;/strong&gt;. Needless to say, I went and bought one as soon as my high-school job allowed me to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The moral of the story is that you need to make products which make people do &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt;. Build something so awesome that it sells itself, I had never seen an Apple commercial or read the tech-specs - but after playing with it in my hands for a couple of minutes I was absolutely sold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some more examples of products like this&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href='http://github.com/'&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href='http://heroku.com/'&gt;Heroku&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href='http://gmail.com/'&gt;Gmail&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href='http://spotify.com/'&gt;Spotify&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href='http://dropbox.com/'&gt;Dropbox&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id='now_stop_sipping_soy_lattes_in_a_cafe_behind_your_macbook_reading_hacker_news_and_pondering_which_company_you_want_your_shitty_little_insignificant_thing_to_be_acquired_by_and_build_something_'&gt;Now stop sipping soy lattes in a cafe behind your Macbook, reading Hacker News and pondering which company you want your shitty little insignificant thing to be acquired by, and build something &lt;i&gt;which makes people's fucking jaw drop&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>What App.net really can be (if we let it)</title>
   <link href="http://zen.id.au/2012/what-appnet-really-can-be-if-we-let-it"/>
   <updated>2012-08-12T00:00:00+10:00</updated>
   <id>http://zen.id.au/2012/what-appnet-really-can-be-if-we-let-it</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;You need to stop thinking that &lt;a href='https://join.app.net'&gt;App.net&lt;/a&gt; is a Twitter clone right now, because it&amp;#8217;s not. Think of the &amp;#8216;alpha&amp;#8217; in alpha.app.net as indicating not only that what we see is an alpha version of their web app (which is powered by the much tech blog ignored API) but an alpha model and example of one of numerous ways to consume the API&amp;#8217;s data. What needs to happen is that &lt;a href='https://join.app.net'&gt;App.net&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#8217;s API becomes a high quality, developer friendly, secure &amp;#8216;social network in a box&amp;#8217;, which developers can use to build applications whom all have &amp;#8216;first class citizen&amp;#8217; access to the user&amp;#8217;s information, posts, messages, relationships, privacy settings etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id='users_as_a_service'&gt;Users as a service&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Developer accounts (or, API access) need to be &amp;#8216;users as a service&amp;#8217;, rather than &amp;#8216;just an API&amp;#8217;. I think the reason people aren&amp;#8217;t going as crazy as they could be over this is that they don&amp;#8217;t realise what it actually is. Tech blogs have been promoting App.net as an alternative to Twitter (which it is, but that&amp;#8217;s only one small part), when it has the potential to become membership to a &amp;#8216;club&amp;#8217; of high quality web communities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id='why_appnet_will_succeed_or_at_least_why_i_think_it_will'&gt;Why App.net will succeed (or at least why I think it will)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has been said by many people (and notably &lt;a href='http://samsoff.es/posts/app-net-is-dreaming-small'&gt;Sam&lt;/a&gt;) that App.net is not throwing a wide enough net. I disagree, I think the choice of targeting developers first is a good one - developers are early adopters by nature, and by (initially) making this a community of primarily tech people they are enlisting the best possible group to give quality feedback about the API. A great API will lead to great things being built on top of it, which will potentially lead to more widespread adoption. Dalton and his team are niching to win and my opinion is that they are doing it right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id='introducing_friendleme'&gt;Introducing &lt;a href='http://www.friendle.me'&gt;Friendle.me&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This morning I upgraded from my backer account to a developer account on &lt;a href='https://join.app.net'&gt;App.net&lt;/a&gt;. There are a few things I&amp;#8217;ve been itching to build, but one particular idea really stood out: &lt;strong&gt;Friendle&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Friendle will be a high quality social community, powered by the App.net API. It will be a way of keeping up with people you know and connect with on &lt;a href='https://join.app.net'&gt;App.net&lt;/a&gt; powered services, you could think of it as a service which draws some ideas from &lt;a href='http://facebook.com'&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href='http://plus.google.com'&gt;Google+&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href='https://alpha.app.net'&gt;alpha.app.net&lt;/a&gt;. For a much more detailed explanation, you can read &lt;a href='http://zensavona.com/2012/introducing-friendle/'&gt;this blog post&lt;/a&gt;. Right now I have just put a splash page up, but you can &lt;a href='http://www.friendle.me/'&gt;register your interest&lt;/a&gt; with your &lt;a href='https://join.app.net'&gt;App.net&lt;/a&gt; account and be notified when an alpha version of Friendle is availble.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Introducing Friendle</title>
   <link href="http://zen.id.au/2012/introducing-friendle"/>
   <updated>2012-08-12T00:00:00+10:00</updated>
   <id>http://zen.id.au/2012/introducing-friendle</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve been using &lt;a href='https://alpha.app.net'&gt;alpha.app.net&lt;/a&gt; for the past few days and it has given me so many ideas as to how a social community should function. Particularly the way conversations and user relationships should be handled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id='both_facebook_and_twitters_approach_to_handling_user_relationships_are_broken'&gt;Both Facebook and Twitters approach to handling user relationships are broken&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Facebook&amp;#8217;s friend system does not scale well (hence the need for like pages, which in turn have their own set of problems), Twitter&amp;#8217;s follower system is better, but still not perfect. I think there can be a better solution, which is why I am building Friendle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Friendle will be a high quality social community, powered by the App.net API. It will be a way of keeping up with people you know and connect with on &lt;a href='https://join.app.net'&gt;App.net&lt;/a&gt; powered services, you could think of it as a service which draws some ideas from &lt;a href='http://facebook.com'&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href='http://plus.google.com'&gt;Google+&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href='https://alpha.app.net'&gt;alpha.app.net&lt;/a&gt;. For a much more detailed explanation, you can read &lt;span&gt;this blog post&lt;/span&gt;. Right now I have just put a splash page up, but you can &lt;a href='http://www.friendle.me/'&gt;register your interest&lt;/a&gt; with your &lt;a href='https://join.app.net'&gt;App.net&lt;/a&gt; account and be notified when an alpha version of Friendle is availble.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id='register_your_interest_now'&gt;&lt;a href='http://www.friendle.me/'&gt;register your interest&lt;/a&gt; now!&lt;/h2&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Why working is a scam</title>
   <link href="http://zen.id.au/2012/why-working-is-a-scam"/>
   <updated>2012-08-06T00:00:00+10:00</updated>
   <id>http://zen.id.au/2012/why-working-is-a-scam</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h3 id='working_a_real_job_is_a_scam'&gt;Working a &amp;#8220;real&amp;#8221; job is a scam.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Australia, the average life expectency is 81. Let&amp;#8217;s assume for a moment that a person starts working full time at 21 and retires at 60, this is assuming you are earning an above average salary (the &amp;#8220;retirement age&amp;#8221; in Australia is actually 65). This means you will work full time for 39 years. If you average 4 full work days per week over your working life, you will have spent just &lt;strong&gt;over 22 years&lt;/strong&gt; at work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id='why_do_we_do_this'&gt;Why do we do this?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unless you are an exception and absolutely love your 9-5 job, you are effectively wasting &lt;strong&gt;over a quarter of your life&lt;/strong&gt; doing something purely to survive. When it&amp;#8217;s put that way, that $100k you earn (if you&amp;#8217;re lucky) sounds pretty unattractive, doesn&amp;#8217;t it? I mean, if you&amp;#8217;re working for your self there is the potential to earn so much more - and that&amp;#8217;s not even the best part&amp;#8230; &lt;strong&gt;Working for yourself frees you from so many restrictions&lt;/strong&gt;. Want to take that 7 day trip to Melbourne? Go for it, just take your laptop along and put in a couple of hours a night in your hotel room. Want to backpack across South East Asia? Go for it!. You can be living any kind of life you want, while your friends are stuck in the office watching the clock and planning their weekend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id='its_not_for_everyone'&gt;It&amp;#8217;s not for everyone&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are happy with your corporate job, good for you. The point of this post is not to tell everyone what they should do, but to point out that if you are not happy doing what you&amp;#8217;re currently doing, &lt;strong&gt;don&amp;#8217;t just suck it up, do something else&lt;/strong&gt; because right now, especially in IT, if your business idea fucks up, there are plenty of other jobs. The days of working with one company and scaling up the corporate ladder until you reach your comfortable seat on a high branch are over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just be prepared for a long and often uncertain journey. The good stuff doesn&amp;#8217;t come easy. &lt;i&gt;(Tim Westergren, Pandora)&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now stop being lazy and go take some risks, &lt;strong&gt;because if you fail, at least you can say you tried&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Why you should never use GoDaddy again</title>
   <link href="http://zen.id.au/2012/why-you-should-never-use-godaddy-ever-again"/>
   <updated>2012-08-02T00:00:00+10:00</updated>
   <id>http://zen.id.au/2012/why-you-should-never-use-godaddy-ever-again</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Although this is untimately my fault, because I had the thought in the back of my mind at the time, I happened to be on GoDaddy&amp;#8217;s site for something work related and had the &amp;#8220;it won&amp;#8217;t happen to me&amp;#8221; mentality at the time, so I quickly checked if an idea for a domain for my side-project was available because it popped to mind in that moment. It was&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;#8220;cool&amp;#8221; I thought, and continued with my work.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, 3 days later, I remembered that domain and went into my webhost&amp;#8217;s (not GoDaddy) control panel to register said domain and run into this&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Error: xxxxxxxxx.com is already registered and is not available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh, really you assholes? A quick whois search and I find this&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Registered through: GoDaddy.com, LLC (http://www.godaddy.com)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I search again for the domain on GoDaddy, they prompt me to buy it with their &amp;#8220;Domain buying service&amp;#8221;, and pay the charges associated. I am not buying the domain out of principle. Go die.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I suppose there is nothing &amp;#8216;wrong&amp;#8217; with this business practice, of analysing the user&amp;#8217;s interest in the domain and buying it if their algorithm thinks that you want it. But I certainly will never use their services again after this. Back to &lt;a href='http://domai.nr/'&gt;domai.nr&lt;/a&gt; for my domain hunting quests.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 
</feed>